Raymond K. Zhao

Academic Qualifications

2018–2022 Doctor of Philosophy,

Faculty of Information Technology, Monash University, Clayton Campus. Supervisors: Ron Steinfeld & Amin Sakzad

02/2016–12/2017 Master of Networks and Security,

Faculty of Information Technology, Monash University, Caulfield Campus.

Masters thesis: "Efficient implementation techniques for lattice-based crypto"

09/2011-06/2015 Bachelor of Engineering,

College of Computer Science & Technology,

Zhejiang University, China.

Speciality: Computer Science & Technology

Scholarships and Awards

04/2018 Dux of Postgraduate (Master of Networks and Security), Cliff Bellamy Awards 2018, Monash University

2018 RTP Stipend, Monash University

2018 Monash International Tuition Scholarship (MITS), Monash University

02/2016 Information Technology International Merit Scholarship, Monash University

Academic Employment

02/2018-now Teaching Associate,

Faculty of Information Technology, Monash University.

Semester 1, 2021 FIT9137 Introduction to computer architecture and networks

Semester 1, 2021 FIT3173 Software security

Semester 1, 2020 FIT9137 Introduction to computer architecture and networks

Semester 1, 2020 FIT5163 Information and computer security

Semester 1, 2020 FIT2093 Introduction to cyber security (Admin Tutor)

Semester 2, 2019 FIT5124 Advanced topics in security (Admin Tutor)

Semester 1, 2019 FIT2093 Introduction to cyber security (Admin Tutor)

Semester 2, 2018 FIT5124 Advanced topics in security

Semester 1, 2018 FIT2093 Introduction to cyber security

06/2017–11/2017 Casual Academic Research Assistant to Dr Amin Sakzad and Dr Ron Steinfeld,

Faculty of Information Technology, Monash University.

Responsibilities:

- Undertaking research duties in the area of Lattice-based Cryptosystems and its Implementation, as directed by the supervisors.
- Improving the efficiency of the Titanium, a new lattice-based cryptosystem proposed by the supervisors and their colleagues.
- Implementing an efficient and timing-attack resistant software implementation of the Titanium.

Professional Profile

- Highly developed research qualitative and analytical skills with a strong capacity to conduct independent research
- Proven ability to conceptualise problems and develop well-reasoned and integrated solutions, as demonstrated throughout research employment and Masters research
- \circ Strong programming skills in C and assembly. Working knowledge of Linux and \LaTeX
- Native speaker of Mandarin

Extra Curricular Activities – Volunteering

07/2016-09/2016 ASK Me Volunteer,

Monash Student Association (MSA), Monash University.

09/2016 Support Crew, Monash MS 24 Hour Mega Swim,

Monash Sport, Monash University.

07/2016 2016 Monash Games Court Operations Volunteer (Fustal),

Monash Sport, Monash University.

Interests

Board games, Card games, Japanese culture

Referees

Dr Ron Steinfeld Dr Amin Sakzad

Senior Lecturer Lecturer

Faculty of Information Technology
Monash University

Faculty of Information Technology
Monash University